Guide to the Talent Identification Program (TIP) Records, 1980-Ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Talent Identification Program (TIP) records 1980-Ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Talent Identification Program. (TIP)
3.0 linear feet Extent: 1700 Items
The Talent Identification Program (TIP) was established in 1980. TIP identifies gifted seventh graders, and the students then spend a summer at Duke taking courses taught by the University's faculty. The program is supported by endowments and fees. The collection includes bulletins, brochures, correspondence, application materials, articles, syllabi, lists of students, flyers and other records.
UA.26.01.0002
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Talent Identification Program (TIP) Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1981.
Historical Note
The Talent Identification Program (TIP) was established in 1980; Robert N. Sawyer was the program's director. TIP identifies gifted seventh graders based on ther SAT and ACT scores. The students then spend a Summer at Duke taking courses taught by the University's faculty; foreign study is also provided. The program is supported by endowments and fees. Sawyer resigned as director in 1990.
Collection Overview
The collection includes bulletins, brochures, correspondence, clippings, application materials, articles, syllabi, lists of students, flyers and other records. Topics include talented students and Duke University faculty.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- Faculty; Press Clippings; Talented Students
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List 1980-Ongoing, 3.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  Files in this collection are arranged into subseries according to their accession numbers. Some files in this collection are restricted by the donor. Administrative records are restricted for 25 years from the date of origin. Please contact research services for more information.
  - Accession A84-53
    - Speeches and Remarks, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
    - Advanced American Studies (materials), 1983 (Box 1)
    - The Experience of Words (materials), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Literary Explorations, parts 1-4, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Latin I-By-Mail (materials), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Latin II-By-Mail (materials), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Latin III-By-Mail (materials), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Intensive German Program (IGP), 1981 (Box 1)
    - By-Mail Program Manual, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - Grammar-By-Mail (materials), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Biology-By-Mail (materials), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Records, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Accession A85-33 (Box 1)
    - Program Records, 1981-1985 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Acession A84-20 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Awards Program, talent search, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Awards Ceremony Programs, 3rd annual talent search, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Clippings, miscellany, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
  - A84-120 (Box 1)
    - Printed Matter (Box 1)
    - Speeches and remarks (Box 1)
    - Bulletins, leaflets, applications, etc. (Box 1)
    - Articles, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Application Forms, brochures, etc., 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
    - "Talent Tabloid," 1982- (Box 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    - Articles (Box 2)
    - Award Ceremony Program, 1984-1987 (Box 2)
    - TIP Newsletter (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1982 RESTRICTED (Box 2)
    - Student Roster, 1981-1983 RESTRICTED (Box 2)
    - Class, Archaeology, 2001 (Box 2)